JUDITH JERUSA APONDI KEY ACCOUNTS RELATIONSHIP MANAGER BOX 104872-00101,

Nairobi, Kenya

Tel No: 0725-102008 / 0754 -717663

Email: judithapondi@yahoo.com

PROFILE

A dedicated person with expertise in navigating organizational success, a team player committed to Providing support and motivation that breeds top performers. An articulate achiever with brilliant interpersonal skills to work at all levels of staff of an organization or ministry. Fluent in English, Kiswahili and basic French. Have exceptional skills in developing concepts and implementing capacity development programs, conferences and seminars in governance and ethics. Currently working with IWay Africa as a Business Development manager.

KEY SKILLS

- 1. Team Player and Assertive.
- 2. Ability to work under pressure and to meet deadlines.
- 3. Communication skills with the ability to interact freely with others.
- 4. Readiness to learn and teach learned skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER IWAY AFRICA-Jan 2018 to date.

- Develop strong relationship with customers at CXO level to maintain baseline growth.
- Follow up on all existing contracts renewal and ensure renewals are done on time.
- Prepare end of month sales reports
- Answering product related questions from customers.
- Delivering excellent customer service.
- Planning projects and activities systematically in line with business priorities.
- Maintaining up to date knowledge of competitor activity, products and services.

KEY ACCOUNT RELATIONSHIP MANAGER- Access Kenya- Internet Solutions October 2012 to March 2017

- Identify growth prospects and specific opportunities within my assigned customer portfolio
- Device strategic plans for relationship penetration and ensure implementation of tactical plan execution including account plan
- and opportunity mapping
- Identify growth opportunities through up-selling and cross selling potential within the assigned customer portfolio
- Provide leadership for customers in understanding business objectives and recommend business solutions to achieve these
- goals
- Develop and execute customer ring fencing strategy
- Develop strong relationship with customers at CXO level to maintain baseline growth
- Follow up on all existing contracts renewal and ensure renewals are done on time.
- Develop responsive solution in conjunction with product innovation team
- Formulate and manage relationships development plans and participate in all customer forums.

- Intimately engagement with relationship fortune accounts
- Submission of weekly reports on accounts performance.
- Enforce real time use of sales info tool by Account Relationship Managers
- Strive to protect existing revenue base by containing churn in all possible cases
- Develop and maintain proactive call and visit plan per customer
 Any other duty assigned to me from time to time.

October 2010 – March 2017:

PUBLIC SECTOR CONSULTANT – Accesskenya Group Ltd

Responsibilities:

- Assume the responsibility of Public Sector Team Leader, by ensuring team members follow up with their monthly pipelines/targets.
- Compile market intelligence, competitor activities and recommend appropriate strategy to increase company market share.
- Ensure growth in business volumes and customer numbers by attaining set revenue targets; monthly, quarterly and annual sales targets as allocated.
- Forecast revenue targets and realize growth and profitability.
- Chair weekly meeting for strategic planning, and teams' pipeline reviews.
- Minimize cost of business operation, and maximize gains.
- Prepare end of month sales reports

Initiated and in charge of developing a competitor Intel reports, to ensure that the company is at par with competition.

July 2009 – September 2010:

Sales Executive - Flash-Com Ltd

Responsibilities:

- Developing and Implementing Customer Value Propositions for small to medium enterprises.
- Boosting revenue and achievement of set sales targets and effective roll out of communication solution developed forth company.
- Consistent identification of communication solutions needs and opportunities for the company.
- Driving growth through acquisition of new accounts and retention of existing accounts by implementing effective retention plans
- Assisting in the implementation of all promotional activities for the company.
- Developing appropriate account for specific sales and trade marketing campaigns to drive adoption of new services within the company.
- Implementing required high quality level of service to the customers.
- Preparing reports on statistical indicators on the performance of the accounts managed as required.

Research Assistant -Centre for Disease (Kibera)

Responsibilities:

- Civic education to local community.
- Distribution of food.
- Assist in distribution of Mosquito Nets to malaria victim.
- Guidance and Counseling and testing for HIV victims.
- Data collection at kibera slum.

Research Assistant - Ministry of Tourism

Responsibilities:

- Marketing tourism destinations, products, attractions and natural resources
- Carrying out research on Inbound and Outbound tourism
- Survey studies and promotion of other tourism circuits
- Promoting Eco Tourism.

Research Assistant - Kenya College of Accountancy University

Responsibilities:

- Identifying gaps that need service delivery improvement in the municipal council department.
- Marketing courses at KCA University.
- Identifying problems at the municipal council department.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Jan 2010 - Dec 2011: Post Graduate Diploma In Marketing

Kenya Institute of Management **Grade Attained:** Upper Credit

Jan 2006- Dec2008: Bachelor of Arts in Tourism

Makerere University **Grade Attained: 3.75**

Jan 2005- Dec 2006: A-levels

Tororo Progressive School

Reference

Name	Position & Institution	Postal Address	Tel and email
_	Head of Business Service	P O Box 63017-00200	0721265591
	and Sales Department	Nairobi	dwambugu@iwayafrica.net
, 0	Head of Key Accounts	P.O.Box43588-00100	0711549994
	Internet solutions Kenya	Nairobi, Kenya	sam.nyaga@internetsolutions.com
Sylvester O. Bolo	Resource Manager	P.O Box 30027-00100	0733-914683
	Ministry of Tourism	Nairobi Kenya	sbolo@tourism.go.ke